[MUSIC]
You should now have a
better understanding of
the basic components of
stock option contracts,
as well as the common
language used by
buyers and sellers
of these products.
But now you may be asking,
what do I have to gain or lose
by trading in this market?
Well, before buying
or selling an option,
you should note that as a rule,
investors are required
among other actions,
to read a copy of
the characteristics
and risks of
standardized options,
also known as the Options
Disclosure Document or ODD.
This booklet which relates
solely to options issued by
the Options Clearing
Corporation or OCC,
provides insights into
the options market,
including the risks faced
by both buyers and sellers,
margin requirements,
tax considerations,
and other topics.
Among other functions and
services the OCC serves as
a central counterparty and
all listed options transactions.
Meaning it provides a guarantee
that a trade will settle,
should an option writer fail to
satisfy their part
of the contract.
You can find out more
about the OCC from
their website as well as
obtain the options
disclosure document.
In general, the
advantages and risks of
trading options mainly depend
on your reason for using them.
Are you looking more
generating additional income,
for example, or hedging
an existing position?
Are you bullish or bearish on
the market and want to speculate
on a stock price over a
fixed period of time?
Well we'll dig more deeply into
these subjects later
in the course.
It's important to note that
what you stand to gain or lose in
the options market is
largely tied to your
market strategy,
as well as at what price
the underlying security needs
to be for you to break-even.
That is neither gain nor
lose on your investment.
Some of the main motives for
options traders to enter the
market include the potential
for enjoying games that
are relatively lower cost
and buying the underlying
security outright in
the stock market,
as well as generating
additional income
and protection against
existing exposure.
Taking a closer look at the
four basic options contracts,
we can see that as a buyer,
your maximum gain is equivalent
to the seller's maximum loss.
In other words, while
the risk faced by
a contract holder is limited
to the premium paid
to the seller,
the writer's risk
can be substantial.
Recall that as an option seller,
you may receive a
relatively small premium
and exchange for acting
as either buyer or seller
to the holder of the
option contract.
If the contract owner
approves correct and
is locked in at a better
price to buy or sell,
it may cost you more as
an option seller in the
open market to fulfill
your obligation to sell
the required shares
for that delivery unless
you already hold them.
If you're an unhedged
seller of a call option,
you could feasibly
face unlimited losses.
For that reason, options trading
is not suitable
for all investors.
There are naturally
several other advantages
for traders to engage
in the options market,
as well as numerous additional
risks that you may face.
Given this, we urge
you to conduct
your own due diligence
depending on your
financial conditions,
investment objectives,
or other requirements.
As you progress
through the course,
you'll also gain a
further understanding of
the nuances that
underlie the upsides and
pitfalls of options
trading for a host of
popular trading strategies
and combinations.
Come back and join us. [MUSIC]